Ramiro Santiago Toulemonde

Senior Frontend Developer | React.js | React Native

Frontend Developer with over 3 years of experience building responsive web and mobile apps. Specialized in React.js and React Native with strong skills in UI/UX, component libraries, and performance optimization. Team player with experience in international projects for the US.

Contact

Location: Santa Rosa, La Pampa, Argentina

Email: ramiro.toulemonde@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramirotoulemonde/

Github: https://github.com/ramirotule

Skills

- React.js, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Styled Components
- Redux Toolkit, MobX State Tree
- Jest, React Testing Library, Selenium
- GitHub, Firebase, GraphQL, Jira, Figma
- Scrum, QA Testing, Deployment (iOS/Android)

Experience

• Frontend Developer at Temperies (Mar 2022 - Present)

Development of mobile and web apps for US clients such as FasterWay and Arculix using React.js and React Native.

• Frontend Developer at A.P.A. – Government Agency (Mar 2019 – Jan 2022)

Migration of legacy systems from Visual FoxPro to modern web apps using React and Firebase.

Owner & Fullstack Dev at RAM Informática (Aug 2008 – Oct 2021)

Custom software development and hardware support. Created a water analysis lab system for provincial use.

Projects Overview

FasterWAY (USA)

MAY 2024 — **PRESENT**

Colaborate in Develop an important desktop and mobile app, The FASTer Way to Fat Loss is the premier virtual itness and nutrition company, teaching clients how to burn fat and live a truly healthy lifestyle through intermittent fasting, carb cycling, macro tracking, whole food nutrition, strategic workouts, and positive mindset.

Technologies: React JS - React Native - Jira - Material UI.

Arculix (USA)

APRIL 2023 — MAY 2024

Continue with the application created in 2022 adding functionalities according to the needs of the client and improvements both in UI (Replacing Blueprint with Material UI) and in the code to improve the performance of the application.

Technologies: React JS – Jira – Material UI - Storybook - Redux Toolkit - Graphql.

FasterWAY (USA)

OCTOBER 2022 — MARCH 2023

Colaborate in QA Testing and Develop an important desktop and mobile app, The FASTerWay to Fat Loss is the premier virtual Fitness and nutrition company, teaching clients how to burn fat and live a truly healthy lifestyle through intermittent fasting, carb cycling, macro tracking, whole food nutrition, strategic workouts, and positive mindset.

Technologies: React JS – Jira – Material UI.

Arculix (USA)

IULY 2022 — SEPTEMBER 2022

Starting from scratch in a project to manage user security issues, access modes, permissions, creating new components and others based on the BlueprintJS library but customizing them according to the client's needs.

Technologies: React JS – Jira – Storybook – BluePrint JS – Graphql.

SecureAuth - Security Issues - Access Modes (USA)

MAY 2022 — JULY 2022

Collaborate in SecureAuth with the Theme & Rebranding, changing the aspect of the interface application.

Technologies: React JS – Figma – CSS.

Umov - Clinic App (CHILE)

APRIL 2022 — MAY 2022

Collaborate in Umov on the development of the backoice web application to handle users that interact with a clinic.

Technologies: React JS – Figma.

Linklabs (USA)

MARCH 2022 — APRIL 2022

Maintenance of the application, adding functions according to the client's needs the application and resolving bugs

Technologies: Vue JS - Figma - Atlassian Suite - Vuetify.

A.P.A. - Government Agency (ARGENTINA)

MARCH 2019 — JANUARY 2022

Migrate Personal application created on Visual FoxPro to Web App.

ABM, Vacations, Salaries, Licenses.

Migrate Purchase application created on Visual FoxPro to Web App.

Tenders, Annual Budget Calculation, Commissions.

Migrate Stock Control application created on Visual FoxPro to Web App.

Technologies: React - Bootstrap 4 - Firebase Database.

Education

Higher Technician in Systems Analysis, UCASAL (2011–2012)

Languages

Spanish (Native), English (B2)